now in the previous lecture we discussed about the planning capability of AI agents.
Now in this lecture we want to take a deep dive into tools and action.
Now depending on the domain of the agent, whether it's an insurance agent, banking agent, travel
agent, it will have different set of tools. So it could have a tool to access database,
maybe SharePoint, through a rag based solution, a code interpreter, whether API travel, booking,
and so on. Previously we had discussed that the large language models do not have access to
whether information and then we saw it cannot book flights. Now this is the shortcoming that tools
calling or function calling fulfill in the case of AI agents. So function calling or tool calling
enable agents to connect and retrieve data from external and internal source data and systems
to enhance the capabilities of the agents. And as we discussed, based on the domain,
there could be different tools that could be at the disposal of the agents. So let's say
it might need to connect to Google search. So it will have a tool to access Google search,
capabilities, maybe weather APIs, if the travel agent, maybe it needs to extract some data from my
SQL database. So it could have a tool using the retrieval augmented solution, maybe you have some
PDF documents on SharePoint, which you need to access. Then you could have a code interpreter
for running custom code. So where this is used is, let's say you have a DevOps agent or a developer
agent and there are some issues in the application and the agent is able to pinpoint the issue
that is causing the application to fail. So what it can do is it can generate some code
using the large language model, which will fix the issue. But before that, it might want to run
that code in a sandbox environment. So that's the code interpreter that is provided to the agent
where it can run the custom code where it can test it out and then apply that patch
to the application, which is failing. Now let's understand the tool calling or function calling
capability through an example. Let's take our vacation planning example and we have the
microcool agent app. Now we know to execute this user request, the agent is going to do the planning
and task decomposition and break it into smaller tasks. And now let's say the first thing
it needs to do is call the weather API. So for that, you can have your first tool. But how do you
create that tool? So let's say in case of AWS, you can use an AWS Lambda service where you
write custom code to call the weather API. And then you let the agent know that if there is any
query related to weather, then you can execute this tool one. Similarly, let's say next it needs to
do the hotel booking. So again, you write some custom code in AWS Lambda and maybe call it tool
two and let the agent know that every time there is a call to book a hotel, you need to execute
this tool to then maybe we discussed about code execution. Maybe it's a developer agent or a
DevOps agent and it generates some code which it needs to test out. So it can use the tool three,
which is a code execution environment provided by the agent. And similarly, let's say if it
needs to call an HR system, then you can have tool four where you have integrated the better
knowledge basis with the agent and you have let the agent know that if there is any question related
to HR system, it needs to execute the tool four. Now, let's try and understand how does the agent
know which tool to call. And an example that I'm showing, we are powering the agent using the
cloud sonnet model from entropic. So what cloud says is that if you want the agent to execute
a particular tool, you have to define the tools available to the agent. So here's a prompt template
editor and this provides instructions to the agent on what tools are available to it and when it
should execute those tools. So here you can see you define the tool name, let's say we define,
okay, the first tool is when you need to call the weather API. So you define the tool name,
weather API, then what are the parameters that will be passed as part of the user request.
So maybe if it's a weather API tool, then the user will pass the location for which it needs the
weather details. So this is how you define and tell the agent what tools are available.
So once you have done that, what entropic says is that once you have defined the prompt template
for the agent and based on this prompt template and the user input, it's going to create a
special system prompt from the tool definition tool configuration and user specified system prompt
that it will feed to the large language model and then it will be able to execute those tools.
So here's another example from entropic. So you can see it is using cloud 3.5
sonnet model and then it provides the details, the tools that you can use. So here it says
the name of the tool is get weather and description is get the current weather in the given
location. And then it says, okay, the user is going to provide you the location and that's a
required field. And then it's going to generate an output which it will pass to the agent and
depending on the context of the user question, it can either synthesize that with other information
from other tools or it can send that output back to the user. Okay, that's pretty much it from
this lecture. I'll see in the next lecture. Thank you.